Mss.B.M828
American Philosophical Society
Sylvanus Griswold Morley diaries,1905-1947
Mss.B.M828
American Philosophical Society
39.0 Volume(s) 39 volumes, typed.
Beginning with his college life as an undergraduate at Harvard (1905-1906), Morley's diaries continue through his earliest travels and explorations of Central America (1907-1944), with information on the study of Mayan hieroglyphs, publications, the study of Central American ruins, and the manners and customs of the jungle Indians. Five volumes are devoted to four separate archaeological expeditions: Copan expedition (1937), Uxmal expedition (1941-1942), Central American expedition (1944), and Guatemala and Honduras expedition (1947). Formal and detailed field notes for the bulk of Morley's archaeological work. There are no diaries for 1908-1911, 1913, 1926-1930, 1933-1936, 1938-1940, and 1943.
39 volumes, typed.
Morley, Sylvanus Griswold, 1883-1948
Volume 1-39
Existence and Location of Originals note
Originals at Peabody Museum, Cambridge, Massachusetts.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Mrs. Sylvanus G. Morley, 1955.
Scope and Contents note
Native American Images note: 106 ink sketches and 105 pencil sketches by archaeologist Sylvanus Morley to illustrate his excavation descriptions of Mayan sites in Yaxchilan (1931), Calakmul (1932), Copan (1937, 1947), and Uxmal (1941-42). Primarily Mayan glyphs, images include diagrams of stairways, pyramids, and ball courts. Referenced in Murphy’s Historical American Sketches, Freeman’s Guide to manuscripts relating to the American Indian, with portions of the journals published, In Search of Maya Glyphs (1970).
Biographical/Historical note
Sylvanus Griswold Morley was an archaeologist and was elected to the American Philosophical Society in 1940.
Harvard University.; Archaeological expeditions -- Central America.; Archaeological expeditions--Honduras; Archaeological expeditions--Mexico; Archaeology -- Central America.; Calakmul Site (Mexico); Central America -- Description and travel.; Copan (Honduras); Diagrams.; Diaries.; Indians of Central America--Languages--Writing; Indians of Central America--Social life and customs; Indians of Mexico--Languages--Writing; Mayan languages--Writing; Sketches.; Uxmal Site (Mexico); Yaxchilan Site (Mexico)
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1905; Vol. 1
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1906; Vol. 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1907; Vol. 3, part 1
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1907; Vol. 3, part 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1908; Vol. 4
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Quirigua Field notes, 1912; Vol. 5
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1914; Vol. 6
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1915; Vol. 7
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Uaxactun Discovery, 1916; Vol. 8
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1917; Vol. 9, part 1
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1917; Vol. 9, part 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1917; Vol. 9, part 3
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Guatemala City, 1918; Vol. 10
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Excavations at Quirigua, 1919; Vol. 11
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1920; Vol. 12
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1921; Vol. 13, part 1
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1921; Vol. 13, part 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1921; Vol. 13, part 3
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1922; Vol. 14, part 1
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1922; Vol. 14, part 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1923; Vol. 15, part 1
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1923; Vol. 15, part 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1923; Vol. 15, part 3
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1923; Vol. 15, part 4
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1923; Vol. 15, part 5
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1923; Vol. 15, part 6
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1923; Vol. 15, part 7
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1924; Vol. 16, part 1
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1924; Vol. 16, part 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley, 1925; Vol. 17
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Yaxchilan Expedition, 22 March-15 May 1931; Part 1
  - Mayan glyphs, 1931
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Yaxchilan Expedition, 22 March-15 May 1931; Part 2
  - Mayan glyphs, 1931
  - Mayan temple, 1931
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Calakmul Expedition, 3 April-1 May 1932; Vol. 19, part 1
  - Mayan glyphs, 1932
  - Mayan glyphs, 1932
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Calakmul Expedition, 3 April-1 May 1932; Vol. 19, part 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Copan Expedition, 1937
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Uxmal Expedition, 1941-1942
  - Great Pyramid, Uxmal, 1941
  - Mayan glyphs, 1941
  - Mayan glyphs, 1941
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Central American Expedition, 1944; Part 1
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Central American Expedition, 1944; Part 2
- Diary of Sylvanus Griswold Morley--Guatemala and Honduras Expedition, 1947